USAMA QURESHI

UNITY GAME & AR/VR DEVELOPER &

usamaqh@gmail.com **1** +(92) 346 5348843

Karachi, Pakistan

ABOUT ME

A seasoned professional in game and AR/VR/MR development, I bring over 7 years of invaluable experience and a diverse skill set. My track record includes collaboration with numerous multinational brands and companies, where I have successfully led teams and delivered impactful projects to the market. Currently based in Karachi, Pakistan, I am open to exciting relocation opportunities that will further enhance my career.

EDUCATION

BACHELOR OF SCIENCE IN SOFTWARE ENGINEERING

Sir Syed University of Engineering & Technology, Karachi 2018

INTERMEDIATE IN PRE-**ENGINEERING**

Govt. College For Men, Karachi 2013

MATRICULATION

Emmi's Institute For Learning, Karachi 2011

DIPLOMA IN GRAPHICS SUITE

Arena Multimedia, Karachi 2012

SKILLS

Unity Game Engine (PC, Android, iOS, WebGL, AR, VR, Photon Multiplayer)

TTS, STT, Localization, Translation API, Social API, Unity VCS, Git, Collab

JSON, Node.js, Unity .jslib, WebRTC, Web sockets, Rest

Vuforia AR, AR Foundation, ARCore, ARKit, Zapworks XR

WORK EXPERIENCE

LEAD AR FULL-STACK DEVELOPER (REMOTE)

| Solution Founder Information Technologies Global | Riyadh Oct 2021 - Present

• Designed and developed innovative market-level products, including a realtime AR coloring book, prototypes for a multiplayer Ludo game, AR weather checking with Midair AR, and real-time AR cosmetics try-on features.

VR & AR DESIGNER & DEVELOPER | Digichowk Pvt. Ltd. | Karachi | Feb 2019 - Oct 2021

- Spearheaded the design and development of innovative, market-driven AR and VR applications, specializing in interactive, industrial-focused solutions for multi-player and cross-platform environments.
- Demonstrated leadership as Team Lead, guiding the project from concept to execution while ensuring alignment with industry standards and client requirements.

SOCIAL MEDIA OFFICER (SOFTWARE DEPARTMENT) | Abbtakk News

| Karachi | Jun 2017 - Nov 2018

- Spearheaded the design and development of innovative AR and VR applications, enhancing user engagement and experience.
- Established and optimized strategic procedures for web, social media, and application development, driving efficiency and effectiveness.

DATABASE DEVELOPER (PART TIME) | QVC Softwares | Karachi

| Jun 2016 - Aug 2016

- Collaborated in a team to develop and optimize databases using SQL Server and Visual C#.
- Seamlessly integrated Visual C# layouts with database functionalities for enhanced user experience.

Oculus Rift, Meta Quest, OpenVR

Blender, Zbrush, Substance Painter

Adobe Suite (Photoshop, Illustrator, Premiere, After Effects)

LANGUAGES

English

Urdu

LINKS

Personal Website:

https://usamaqh.github.io/usam

agureshi/

LinkedIn:

https://www.linkedin.com/in/us

amagh/

HONORS & AWARDS

MICROSOFT'S IMAGINE CUP REGIONAL WINNER | Microsoft

ALL KARACHI PROJECT COMPETITION WINNER | SSUET

HUPEC FYP COMPETITION WINNER | *Hamdard University*

ZUFEST ZURIC PROJECT COMPETITION WINNER | *Ziauddin University*

SEMINAR ON VIRTUAL & AUGMENTED REALITY - INVITED SPEAKER \mid SSUET

TECH MOTIVATIONAL SPEAKER | SSUET

ALUMNUS GUEST SPEAKER | *SSUET*